Michael Lewis

513-254-1822 | michaellewis1689@outlook.com | Xenia, OH 45385 https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-lewis-74b6143/ | https://michaellewis.netlify.app/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am an expert web developer with over 15 years of experience building high quality and performant websites following mobile-first, component-based design and agile development methodologies. I have experience with Full Stack web development, CRM setup and migration, Data Engineering and eCommerce. I have a certification from Acquia for Drupal development, and my work on City of Hope has won an award. I've worked with teams of various sizes in various roles, all the way up to team lead. I am fully set up to work remotely but am willing to relocate if necessary. I'm looking for an opportunities to lead web development teams, use emerging technologies like AI, and spec into data engineering

EXPERIENCE

ICF 12/2023 - Present

- Senior Software Engineer contributing to the development of the backend of https://data.cms.gov for the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Services built on Drupal.
- Architected technical solutions for designed user interface updates to node creation forms
- Supported team development by reviewing pull requests and cross testing code
- Improved the code base's PHPUnit code coverage by writing and improving unit tests
- Troublehooting bugs with the JSON API and the site's bespoke dataset import and export features.
- Coordinating releases and updates between the front-end and back-end teams.

Technology Specialist, VML (via TekSystems)

11/2021 - 11/2023

- Managing a team that developed the Lutron Luxury V2 site https://luxury.lutron.com).
 Created a content hub of Case Studies by Designers Who use Lutron
 Products.Gathered requirements. Developed technical strategy/architecture. Build components with Acquia Site Studio. Managed dev and release CI/CD with Bitbucket and Jenkins. Managed site configuration.
- Lead the team that built https://www.cityofhope.org. Won the 2022 eHealthcare Alliance Platinum award for Best Site Design for a Hospital with 200-399 Beds. Gathered requirements. Developed technical strategy/architecture. Managed SDLC with CI/CD from Microsoft Azure DevOps to Acquia.
- Architected and executed content migration to Drupal 8 from Oracle WebCenter Sites.
 Configured Apache Solr search with Facets and custom plugins. Developed
 Ratings/Reviews component with data from Binary Fountain REST API.
- Developed an ETL pipeline DAG in Python using Google Cloud Composer to facilitate the migration of CRM from Salesforce to Braze for Wendy's.

- Rebuilt the MyFembree website for Pfizer using ReactJS (Gatsby) with a fresh mobile-first component-based design and improved sitemap. Developed CI/CD Pipelines in Bitbucket to deploy the site to an AWS server hosting environment.
- Developed updates to https://www.vml.com. Migrated content from another Drupal 8 site to merge the sites. Executed a full rebrand of the site from VMLY&R to VML using search/replace queries and scripts. Implemented design refresh. Migrated code repository from Bitbucket to Github. Set up Github Actions to use ESLint, PHPCS and Gulp to test and build the site in CI/CD pipeline.Configured Apache Solr Search.
- Upgraded https://www.wendys.com from Drupal 8 to Drupal 9. Fixed media and path alias bugs.

Senior Drupal Developer, NLRB (via Puyenpa)

05/2020 to 11/2021

- Senior Drupal Developer and Technical Architect for https://www.nlrb.gov
- Completed migration from Drupal 7 to Drupal 8
- Gathered Requirements
- Implemented Spanish Translations
- Implemented Apache Solr Search
- Architected and developed a download manager for large CSV exports.
- Set up improvements to Dev -> Stage -> Prod release lifecycle.
- Implemented Automated Testing using Katalon (a proprietary wrapper for Selenium) and Backstop JS.
- Configured Simple SAML single sign-on with Login.gov.
- Architected and developed a feature to allow users to follow cases and regional news on a dashboard.
- Maintained compliance of the website with the high security standards that all federal computer systems must adhere to.
- Solved website performance problems.
- Filed CAB requests and represented the Web team on CAB board to obtain approval for deployemetns.

Senior Drupal Developer, Duo Consulting

01/2017 - 04/2020

- Built the new website for Freeborn & Peters LLP. Migrated Drupal 7 to Drupal 8
- Built an online eCommerce point of sale for Chicago Botanic Garden with a Gateway/eGalaxy backend.
- Updated and Maintained websites for Bosch (Dremel), Much Shelist, P.C., Bracewell LLP, Figo Pet Insurance, Domu Chicago, Kettering University, and others.

Senior Drupal Developer, TQINet/The Beracha Foundation

07/2008 - 12/2016

- Developed an online e-commerce system for WCSG Radio in Cornerstone, Michigan to drive their bi-annual pledge drives.
- Administered Web, DNS, and Mail servers. Architected hosting environments. Managed Purchase orders for new server hardware. Created a highly available shared hosting environment for web sites.

- Managed migration of numerous servers from one data center to a new one over 20 miles away with minimal downtime. We completed the move while maintaining our SLAs.
- Built a Drupal Commerce based non-profit fundraising system so organizations can promote their campaigns in a social friendly system that engages prospective donors to give to the cause.
- Built numerous websites using Drupal, PHP Zend Framework, or just plain HTML/CSS/JS.
- Built ECommerce donation pages
- Built a REST API intermediary for an auction system to communicate with eTapestry's SOAP API.
- API and ETL integrations of data into the Etapestry CRM using their SOAP API

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts, Management Information Systems

05/2006

Cedarville, University

SKILLS

Drupal, Linux, Apache HTTPD, LAMP, MySQL, PHP, HTML, XHTML, HTML5, CSS3, CSS, JavaScript, SASS, Node.js, React, Python, Google Cloud Platform, Acquia, Pantheon, Docker, DNS, SSL, CDN, Apache Solr, Facets, Github Actions, Microsoft Azure, Atlassian (JIRA/Bitbucket), Figma, Bootstrap, Twig, Networking, Server Configuration, Tailwind, Slack, Jenkins, Postgresql, Version Control, UI, User Experience, VPN, JSON, CI/CD, RDBMS, Scrum, Front-End, Back-End, Full-Stack, Sprint Planning, Computer Science, Restful Services, Automated Testing, Quality Assurance, Responsive Design, Security Clearance, Continuous Integration, Cross-Browser Compatibility, Presentation Skill, Flexible, Committed, Articulate, Problem Solving, Analytical Skills, Attention to Detail, Time Management Skills, Strong Critical Thinking, Katalon, Selenium, Backstop JS, CMS, Git, Devops, jQuery, Taxonomy, Develop Software, Web Applications, Programming Languages, Test-Driven Development, Source Control Management, Leadership, Collaboration, Teamwork skills, Passion to Learn, Written Communication, ServiceNow, SOAP, Chrome, Debugging, Typescript, Wireframes, Website Design, Email experience, Website Development, Technical Assistance, Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC), Self-motivated, Innovative

AWARDS/RECOGNITIONS/VOLUNTEER WORK - (OPTIONAL)

• 2022 <u>eHealthcare Alliance Platinum award for Best Site Design for a Hospital with 200-399 Beds</u>.

•

Acquia Certified Drupal Developer.

April, 2018

2022

- Sunday School Teacher
- Soccer Coach
- Amateur Musician